

6-3208 TianJuYuan, ChaoYang District, Beijing, China

□ (+86) 185-1115-8693 | ■ qudongfang@gmail.com | ★ http://www.concurrent.work/ | ☑ qudongfang

Summary _

Current Senior Software Engineer @JD.COM. Contributor of OpenTSDB, docker (moby), pinpoint and a few other opensource projects. JVM sourcecode hacker. 5+ years experience specializing in backend. Expert in root cause analysis and troubleshooting. Interested in devising a better problem-solving method for challenging tasks, and learning new technologies and tools if the need arises.

Work Experience _____

JD.COM. Beijing, China

SR. SOFTWARE ENGINEER/ARCHITECT

Apr. 2016 - now

- · Monitoring client which collects metrics about servers/apps/domains/etc; Role: Project leader and core developer.
- · Cluster computing of metrics for monitoring purpose such as realtime pageviews/response time; Role Project leader and core developer.
- · Monitoring web gateway which services as the backend of dashboards and graphs; Role Project leader and core developer.
- CloudWatch product of JDCloud.com like CloudWatch from AWS; Role: Architect And developer.

PassionTec(Meituan-Dianping)

Beijing, China

SR. SOFTWARE ENGINEER May. 2015 - Apr. 2016

• Building a Saas platform on intelligent restaurant management to help the managers or owners; Role: Lead developer.

Baidu, Inc.

SR. DEVOPS ENGINEER (WORK AS A SOFTWARE ENGINEER WITH DEVOPS ENGINEER TITLE)

Beijing, China Jun. 2013 - May. 2015

• Building realtime big data processing platform serviced as backed of monitoring; Role: Developer.

• Building central logging platform to store/query logs; Role: Developer.

Skills____

General Cloud Computing, Root Cause Analysis, Troubleshooting, Site Reliability Engineering

Platform Linux, FreeBSD, Docker(moby)

Big Data Kafka, Storm, Spark, Elastic Stack(ELK) Back-end Thrift, Spring, Ruby on Rails, REST API Database MySQL, Redis, SQLite, OpenTSDB

Programming Java, Golang, Python, Ruby, Bash, Racket

Languages English, Chinese

Education

Renmin University of China

Beijing, China

BACHELOR CANDIDATE IN COMPUTER SCIENCE

Sep. 2018 - Jul. 2021

· Distance learning.

Nanjing Normal University

Nanjing, China

M.S. IN GEOGRAPHIC INFORMATION SCIENCE AND CARTOGRAPHY

Sep. 2010 - Jun. 2013

- Got a research thesis Scholarship which are given to exceptional students in University.
- Got twice Scholarships which are given to promising students in this University.

Henan University of Urban Construction

Pingdingshan, China

B.S. IN GEOGRAPHIC INFORMATION SCIENCE AND CARTOGRAPHY

Sep. 2005 - Jul. 2009

- · Got a National Scholarship which are given to outstanding students in China.
- · Got 6 times Scholarships which are given to promising students in this University.